Guide to the J. M. Barrie Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1686–1955; Series I; 8.13; 20 boxes
  - Third-Party Letters About J. M. Barrie
    - Asquith, Cynthia, Lady
      - to Hilda Trevelyan, 1955 December 14 (Box 20, Folder 646)
        Removed from Peter Pan (London: Hodder and Stoughton, 1928) (BEIN Ip B276 P45 1928E)
      - to an unidentified recipient, 1921 May 1 (Box 20, Folder 647)
        Expressing Barrie's regret at the death of Alf Hayman and reporting the death of Barrie's ward, Michael Llewelyn Davies; signed "C. Greene."
      - Miscellaneous correspondence and contracts regarding literary and film rights to Barrie's writings, 1945–1953 (Box 20, Folder 648)
        Includes contract for film rights to Farewell Miss Julie Logan.
    - Bergner, Elisabeth, to John Martin-Harvey, 1935–1936 (Box 20, Folder 649)
      Concerning the production of The Boy David.
    - Birrell, Augustine to Mary Ansell, 1902 November 20 (Box 20, Folder 650)
      Replying to an invitation to tea at the home of Mary and James Barrie.
    - Boucicault, Dion, to Ford Madox Ford, 1906 March 20 (Box 20, Folder 651)
      Regarding reading his play "Tilda."
    - Bright, Addison, to unidentified recipient, undated (Box 20, Folder 652)
      Regarding Quality Street.
    - Buchan, John, to Max Robinson, 1923 October 9 (Box 20, Folder 653)
    - Caine, Hall, to E. F. H. Capy, 1906 (Box 20, Folder 654)
      Concerning the Nottingham bazaar.
    - Carter, Huntly, to Bernard Shaw, 1930 June 3 (Box 20, Folder 655)
      Inquiring about Shaw's participation in the film The Cinema Supper at the Savoy. Shaw's reply is on the verso.
    - Chase, Pauline, to Mr. de Gray, undated (Box 20, Folder 656)
      Concerning a book to be sold at the theatre while she is playing in Peter Pan.
    - Cochran, C. B., to J. B. Booth, 1941 (Box 20, Folder 657)
      Removed from The Plays of J. M. Barrie. The Boy David (London, 1938)
    - Cooper, Duff, to Gerald Barry, 1927–1930 (Box 20, Folder 658)
      Includes one autograph letter, signed, from Barrie to Cooper.
    - Daniell, Alfred
      Much of the material in this group relates to Barrie's Edinburgh landlady Helen Chalmers Edwards (1819-1929). Barrie would visit her when he returned to town, and placed a bench at the Royal Infirmary in her memory.
      - to M. C. Herriot, 1932 (Box 20, Folder 659)
        Miss Herriot was a nurse in the hospital ward and took care of Mrs. Edwards at the end of her life.
      - regarding Mrs. Edwards, 1899–1929 (Box 20, Folder 660)
        The folder holds correspondence from L. A. Reid and others, as well as newspaper clippings.
      - newspaper clippings regarding Barrie and Mrs. Edwards, 1929 (Box 58 (Oversize), Folder 1167)
      - regarding the Daniell family, 1686–1937 (Box 20, Folder 661)
        Contains family documents and letters.
    - Donald, Robert, to Thomas Lennox Gilmour, 1914 (Box 20, Folder 662)
      Concerning publication details of Barrie's Der Tag. Accompanied by a copy of a typed letter dated December 13, 1914, from Gilmour to Donald and a typed letter, signed, to Gilmour from Donald's secretary.
    - Du Maurier, Gerald, to editor of The Bookman, 1920 September 30 (Box 20, Folder 663)
    - Edeson, Robert, to Mrs. Scudder, 1901 (Box 20, Folder 664)
    - Ervine, St. John G., to Thomas Moult, 1928 March 8 (Box 20, Folder 665)
      Concerning an exchange of letters to the editor of the Observer between Moult and Ervine. Enclosure: typed letter (carbon copy) to the editor of the Observer, March 8, 1928, replying to Moult's criticism of Ervine's review of Moult's Barrie (London: Jonathan Cape Ltd., 1928).
    - Frampton, George, to Mr. Wright, 1912 January 20 (Box 20, Folder 666)
      Concerning the Peter Pan statue for Kensington Gardens.
    - French, Daniel Chester, to Mr. Thomas, 1914 September 25 (Box 20, Folder 667)
      Replying to Thomas's invitation to meet Barrie.
    - Frohman, Charles, to Walter P. Eaton, 1908 October 1 (Box 20, Folder 668)
    - George VI, King of Great Britain, to Peter Llewelyn Davies, 1937 June 19 (Box 20, Folder 669)
      Telegram expressing his sympathy on the death of Barrie.
    - Gilmour, Thomas Lennox
      - to H. H. Asquith, 1915 July (Box 20, Folder 670)
        Concerning the War Loan.
      - to the editor of the Times (London, England), 1916 (Box 20, Folder 671)
    - Gissing, George
      - to "Katie" [Catherine Gissing], 1892 February 13 (Box 20, Folder 672)
        Containing references to Barrie and Rudyard Kipling.
      - to Harry Hick, 1898 November 18 (Box 20, Folder 673)
        Criticizing the current published work of Barrie, Rudyard Kipling, James George Frazer, Clement King Shorter, and mentioning William E. Gladstone and Edward Clodd.
    - Granville-Barker, Harley
      - to William Farren, 1913 August 6 (Box 20, Folder 674)
        Concerning an opportunity for Farren to act in a play by Barrie.
      - to Gilbert Murray, 1912 (Box 20, Folder 675)
        Concerning opposition by Barrie, George Bernard Shaw, Rudyard Kipling and Thomas Hardy to the government censorship of Eden Phillpotts' play The Secret Woman.
    - Hardy, Thomas, to William Morris Colles, 1895; 1905 (Box 20, Folder 676)
    - Hewlett, Maurice Henry, to Mary Ansell, 1909; undated (Box 20, Folder 677)
      Letter of October 25 refers to the dissolution of the marriage of Barrie and Mary Ansell.
    - Higginson, Thomas Wentworth, to unidentified recipients, 1892 May (Box 20, Folder 678)
      Asking for support to organize a Society of American Authors.
    - Hodder-Williams, Ralph Wilfred, to unidentified recipient, 1946 October 28 (Box 20, Folder 679)
    - Jacks, L. P. (Lawrence Pearsall), to Cynthia Asquith, 1934 May 7 (Box 20, Folder 680)
    - James, Henry, to Gilbert Cannan, 1914 March 20 (Box 20, Folder 681)
    - Konow, Ingeborg von der Lippe, to John Beveridge, 1896 March 21 (Box 20, Folder 682)
      Requesting an explanation from Beveridge of some Scottish terms in Barrie's The Little Minister; in Norwegian.
    - Lane, John, to Elkin Mathews, 1891 (Box 20, Folder 683)
      Probably concerning arrangements to secure Barrie, [Hubert?] Bland or [Richard Le Gallienne] to do an article on [George Meredith]
    - Lang, Andrew, to Mrs. Oliphant, 1888 October 29 (Box 20, Folder 684)
      Describing Barrie as the "humourist (a little wi' delficulty) for St James's Gazette ."
    - Llewelyn Davies, George
      - to Margaret Llewelyn Davies, 1906 April 19 (Box 20, Folder 685)
      - to Michael Llewelyn Davies, 1908 June 15 (Box 20, Folder 686)
        Sends birthday greetings and news of his activities at Eton. Mutilated.
    - Llewelyn Davies, John, to Michael Llewelyn Davies, 1908 (Box 20, Folder 687)
    - Llewelyn Davies, Nicholas, to Hilda Trevelyan, 1934 August 4 (Box 20, Folder 688)
    - Llewelyn Davies, Peter
      - to George Llewelyn Davies, 1915 January 11 (Box 20, Folder 689)
      - to Thomas Moult, 1927 November 17 (Box 20, Folder 690)
        Concerning Moult's Barrie (London: Jonathan Cape Ltd., 1928).
      - to Hilda Trevelyan, 1955 December 5 (Box 20, Folder 691)
    - Mabie, Hamilton Wright, to Edmund Clarence Stedman, 1896 October 27 (Box 20, Folder 692)
      Inviting Stedman to a dinner at the Aldine Club in honor of Barrie.
    - Mason, A. E. W. (Alfred Edward Woodley), to Cynthia Asquith, undated (Box 20, Folder 693)
    - Meredith, William Maxse, to Charles Scribner, 1909 November 9 (Box 20, Folder 694)
      Concerning the dissolution of the marriage of Barrie and Mary Ansell.
    - Milne, A. A. (Alan Alexander)
      - to Mr. Parker, 1952 August 3 (Box 20, Folder 695)
        Containing an anecdote about Barrie.
      - to an unidentified person, 1921 December 11 (Box 20, Folder 696)
        Expressing the opinion that he would rather be a "Chelsea Barrie" than an "English Leacock." Letter is written in the hand of "Celia."
    - Moult, Thomas, to the editor of the Observer, 1928 March 15 (Box 20, Folder 697)
      Replying to St. John G. Ervine's letter to the editor of the Observer, March 8, 1928, concerning Moult's Barrie (London: Jonathan Cape Ltd., 1928).
    - Nicoll, William Robertson, to Miss Wilmot, 1897 Sep? (Box 20, Folder 698)
      Concerning Miss Wilmot's poems sent to him by Barrie.
    - Noyes, Alfred, to Thomas Moult, 1928 (Box 20, Folder 699)
    - Partridge, Bernard, to an unidentified recipient, 1931 June 13 (Box 20, Folder 700)
      Concerning the sale of his copy of Richard Savage by Barrie and H. B. Marriott Watson, and the prologue to the play by W. E. Henley.
    - Phillpotts, Eden, to Mr. Robertson, 1927 July 2 (Box 20, Folder 701)
    - Rackham, Arthur, to Gertrude Simmons Pearson, 1927; 1930 (Box 20, Folder 702)
      Discussing models used in his drawings, mentioning his illustrations for Barrie's Peter Pan, and supplying a list of his drawings for sale.
    - Reform Club. London, to T. Wemyss Reid, 1893 December 8 (Box 20, Folder 703)
      Acknowledging Reid's proposal of Barrie for membership in the club.
    - Rolland, Romain, to Gilbert Cannan, 1910; undated (Box 20, Folder 704)
    - Sadleir, Michael, to Mr. Bailey, 1929 September 10 (Box 20, Folder 705)
      Concerning George Meredith.
      Removed from George Meredith, 1909, by J. M. Barrie (London: Constable and Co., 1909) (BEIN Ip B276 G4, copy 2)
    - Seaman, Owen, to Thomas Lennox Gilmour, 1932 (Box 20, Folder 706)
    - Seton, Ernest Thompson, to Mary Ansell, 1904 December 18 (Box 20, Folder 707)
      Apologizing for not being able to call on the Barries and to confer on Mr. Barrie "the high degree of chief of the Council Fire."
    - Shaw, Bernard, to Katherine Pole, 1923 July 14 (Box 20, Folder 708)
      Commenting on the "Milton incident" and Barrie.
    - Tarkington, Booth, to Miss Avery, 1900 March 25 (Box 20, Folder 709)
      Discussing Barrie's Tommy and Grizel and the work of George Bernard Shaw.
    - Terry, Dame Ellen, to Constable and Co., 1909 December 27 (Box 20, Folder 710)
      Containing an order for six copies of Barrie's George Meredith, 1909 (London: Constable and Co., 1909).
    - Thurston, Frank, to unidentified recipient, 1929 January 13 (Box 20, Folder 711)
    - Trevelyan, Hilda, to Edmund J. Caley, 1906; 1907; undated (Box 20, Folder 712)
      Two of the letters are signed "Wendy," a character in J. M. Barrie's Peter Pan which Miss Trevelyan portrayed for many years.
    - Wareing, Alfred, to Thomas Moult, 1928 March 12 (Box 20, Folder 713)
      Concerning Moult's reply to St. John G. Ervine's review of Moult's Barrie (London: Jonathan Cape Ltd., 1928).
    - Wells, H. G. (Herbert George)
      - to Mary Ansell, circa 1910 (Box 20, Folder 714)
        Concerning the dissolution of the marriage of Barrie and Mary Ansell, with reference to Wells' marital status.
      - to Gilbert Cannan, circa 1913 (Box 20, Folder 715)
        Concerning Cannan's Round the Corner (London: Martin Secker, 1913).
    - Williams, John D., to Walter Prichard Eaton, 1915 November 25 (Box 20, Folder 716)
    - Withers, Hartley, to Thomas Lennox Gilmour, 1915 July 13 (Box 20, Folder 717)
      Concerning Barrie's letter about World War I loans.
    - Zukor, Adolph, 1920–1925 (Box 20, Folder 718)
      Correspondence between Zukor, Maude Adams, Jesse L. Lasky, J. M. Barrie, Daniel Frohman, Gilbert Miller, and William Wiseman relating to the first film version of Peter Pan.
- Writings, 1876–1954; Series II; 16.5; 35 boxes
  The series spans Barrie's literary output in terms of time and type in both personal and professional efforts. Found here are examples of his earliest and latest plays— Bandelero the Bandit (1877) and The Boy David (1936)—as well as parts of some novels in manuscript, proofs sheets, and serial forms, and a selection of speeches, prefaces, articles, and essays he wrote for a variety of audiences. Like the rest of the J. M. Barrie Collection, material in this series was accumulated in independent acquisitions over several decades, and therefore does not provide a comprehensive view of Barrie's creative process for any of the titles present. For the same reason, not all of his titles in any genre are represented here. Perhaps because the autograph manuscripts, play scripts in particular, were so valued by their owners, this series contains several fine bindings by noted English binderies: three by Douglas Cockerell & Son, three by Morrell, London, four by Sangorski & Sutcliffe, and at least three by Riviere & Sons.
  The Notebooks subseries contains a group of bound volumes owned and used by Barrie over his lifetime for working out drafts of his writings and noting other creative ideas. Notebooks 1 through 42 are literary in nature and are arranged roughly in chronological order from 1880 to the 1930s. Notebooks 43 and 44 hold addresses of friends and colleagues. Notebook 45 is a small scrapbook/commonplace book made by Wellwood Anderson (1859-1940), Barrie's friend from school days in Dumfries. It contains material primarily related to that formative period in Barrie's life, as does Notebook 46.
  Plays and Other Scripts comprise the bulk of the series. This subseries holds a wide variety of Barrie's writings for performances, ranging from notes to drafts to finished manuscript and typescript versions, most of the latter with autograph corrections and additions. Also filed here are notes and scripts for a ballet, films, private theatricals, and party skits, as well as related music scores by John Crook and Gustav Saenger. The two works with the greatest extent of material are Barrie's most popular play, Peter Pan, and his last play, The Boy David. Many scripts bear labels or stamps of typing services, as well as the initials and annotations of their owners, in particular the actresses Elisabeth Bergner and Irene Vanbrugh, and the director Theodore Komisarjevsky. Photographs from stage and film productions are filed in Series III, as are some programs and printed sheet music from Peter Pan.
  The final subseries, Other Writings, holds two of his most noted nonfiction works, the autobiographical collection The Greenwood Hat, and Margaret Ogilvy, a biography of his mother, along with a group of speeches, prefaces, articles, essays, reviews, and poems. This material, and several letters in the correspondence files of Series I, show Barrie's interest in the topics of censorship, cricket, George Meredith, and World War I and its long shadow.
  Series II is organized into six subseries: Notebooks, Novels, Plays and Other Scripts, Prefaces, Speeches,; and Other Writings.
  - Notebooks
    The notebook numbers were assigned by the library. A partial list of contents accompanies each volume; excerpts from some of the notebooks appear in The Story of J. M. B.: a Biography by Denis Mackail (London: Peter Davies, 1941).
    Notebooks 1-44 are arranged in chronological order.
    - Notebook 1, 1880–1885 (Box 21, Folder 719-720)
      Signed on flyleaf. Autograph manuscript of a three-act comedy, Bohemia, A New and Original Comedy in Three Acts, written on rectos, with sketches for stage settings facing pages 2, 37, and 71. Versos contain: The Men, The Real over pressure, The Cricket Spell, Freeman, Mark Tapley, M.P., The Body in the Black Box, The Trade of Bookmaking, An analysis of prefaces, Cricket at our village and four untitled items. Accompanied by an index. Bound in purple cloth; with autograph manuscript notes and parts for Bohemia. [216] p., 21 cm.
    - Notebook 2, 1881 October 6 (Box 21, Folder 721)
      Pages 53-66 are laid in loose. Contents: A Specially Selected Company; Lear's Fool; Heroines; Standard; and notes for titles, dialogues and articles, Reversed the notebook contains Maggie [Margaret] Barrie's signature on back cover and French exercises in her hand. Accompanied by an index. Bound in purple cloth. [92] p., 23 cm.
    - Notebook 3, 1882–1885 (Box 21, Folder 722-723)
      Bound in three-quarter red leather stamped in gold on front cover: "Index Rerum. Dew Darneson." Accompanied by an index giving place and date of publication when known. Manuscript title page in the hand of Wellwood Anderson: Index Rerum. forming a handy book of ready reference... for the private use of Dew. Darneson. Dumfries. 1879. Barrie's manuscript note on title page: "This book was given to me by Dew Darneson (Wed Anderson) at Dumfries 1882 when he had long abandoned the scheme sketched in the title page. It contains the articles &c, or the original ideas of them, that I sent to the London press (chiefly St James Gazette) during my first year or two in London and for some months in Dumfries before I went there. Some of them were later developed into my Auld Licht books &c JMB. 1929. This is not the order in which they were written. I jumped about thru the pages." This notebook contains 101 items, including an early version of Better Dead. [502] p., 27 cm.
    - Notebook 4, 1885–1886 (Box 22, Folder 724-725)
      Accompanied by an index giving place and date of publication when known. Back cover wanting. [200] p., 23 cm.
    - Notebook 5, 1903–1906 (Box 22, Folder 726-727)
      Contents: Problem Play [A Slice of Life], One Act from my WEWK idea [What Every Woman Knows]; The Tin Wedding; Peter Pan revise, May 7, 1906; Barrister play; Drink play [Old Friends]; and The Sabine Women. Accompanied by an index. Bound in red cloth. [262 p., 189 blank], 23 cm.
    - Notebook 6, 1885-1888? (Box 22, Folder 728)
      A partial list of contents: Why Men Smoke; Better Dead; Advice To Those Who Write to the Editor; Gretna Green; Vagabond Students; When A Man's Single; My Popular Sister; and ideas for the Auld Licht stories. [125] p., 13 cm.
    - Notebook 7, 1887-1888? (Box 22, Folder 729)
      Note on paste-down endpaper: The Bluestocking Notes Houseboat Vol 1. [94] p., 11 cm.
    - Notebook 8, 1888? (Box 22, Folder 730)
      A partial list of contents: The Houseboat Granny; The Blue Stocking Notes, vol. 2; Woman's Wit; and many notes on Charles Darwin. [52] p., 11 cm.
    - Notebook 9, 1888 (Box 22, Folder 731)
      A partial list of contents: [The] Third Sex; Houseboat Granny; Barber; Meredith; and notes for The Little Minister, An Edinburgh Eleven, and stories about Thrums. [142] p., 14 cm.
    - Notebook 10, 1889 (Box 23, Folder 732)
      Dated November 2, 1889. A partial list of contents: Novel: Blotted out: story of married life; and notes for The Little Minister. [102] p., 11 cm.
    - Notebook 11, 1890 (Box 23, Folder 733)
      Signed and dated March 25, 1890. A partial list of contents: Father and Son; notes and revisions for The Little Minister. [98] p., 10 cm.
    - Notebook 12, 1890 (Box 23, Folder 734)
      Signed and dated September 4, 1890. A partial list of contents: Houseboat; Queen Mary's Ring; Opera; Dancing Girl: a music hall drama in four turns; Becky Sharpe; Illegitimate child story; and revisions for The Little Minister. [178] p., 14 cm.
    - Notebook 13, 1892 (Box 23, Folder 735)
      Signed and dated March 14, 1892. A partial list of contents: Bookworm [The Professor's Love Story]; P.L [Painted Lady]; Self Made Woman; and notes about marriage. [100] p., 11 cm.
    - Notebook 14, 1892 (Box 23, Folder 736)
      Signed and dated March 28, 1892. A partial list of contents: Robert Louis Stevenson's address; Bkwm [A Professor's Love Story]; S.T. [Sentimental Tommy]; Why Men Smoke; Find The Woman; P.M. and notes relating to the death of William Winter, May 1892. [228] p., 12 cm.
    - Notebook 15, 1892-1902? (Box 23, Folder 737)
      A partial list of contents: The Case Is Altered [The Admirable Crichton]; Ghost Story; WEWK [What Every Woman Knows]; Fairy Tales; LWB [Little White Bird]; Phoebe [Quality Street]; Brookfield Story; and Adventurers Play. [116] p., 10 cm.
    - Notebook 16, 1894 (Box 23, Folder 738)
      Signed and dated March 10, 1894. A partial listing of contents: P.L. (Painted Lady]; S.T. [Sentimental Tommy]; The Neighbour's Bairn; Scotch Wedding [The Wedding Guest]; and notes about Thomas Hardy. [152] p., 11 cm.
    - Notebook 17, 1898 (Box 23, Folder 739)
      Signed and dated June 1898. A partial list of contents: Ghost Story. The Little Old Lady; Piggy-Wig; The Duchess; Play [What Every Woman Knows]; and revisions for Tommy and Grizel. [90] p., 9 cm.
    - Notebook 18, 1899 (Box 24, Folder 740)
      A partial list of contents: Schoolboy; Pantomime. Cinderella and Dog; The Censor and His Views; Queen Play; Strongman Play; The Woman Who Could Not Love; Boy; Peter's Will; revisions for Tommy and Grizel; and notes for What Every Woman Knows and The Admirable Crichton. [90] p., 9 cm.
    - Notebook 19, 1899 (Box 24, Folder 741)
      Signed and dated November 16, 1899. A partial list of contents: Barbara Story. A Child's book; The Man Who Came Back play; Philanthropist play; The Smart Set play; Book of Ghost Stories of the War; The Little White Bird; Schoolboy; and Bohemians. [134] p., 11 cm.
    - Notebook 20, 1902? (Box 24, Folder 742)
      A partial list of contents: LWB [Little White Bird]; [The] Man Who Came Back; Napoleonic Wars play; The Thrums Fairy Tales; Boys; Babies Pantomime; A Frenzy of Grandeur; Fairy Play; On The Attractiveness of Old Ladies; Should Literary Men Wear Uniforms?; Four Plays in 30 Minutes; and the complete plot of The Admirable Crichton under the headings of Irene Play, The Smart Set, The Island, and The Case Altered. [90] p., 9 cm.
    - Notebook 21, 1901–1902 (Box 24, Folder 743)
      Contains notes for The Admirable Crichton; many pages blank. [90] p., 9 cm.
    - Notebook 22, 1902 (Box 24, Folder 744)
      Signed and dated [March] 13, 1902. Partial list of contents: Case Altered [The Admirable Crichton]; The Little White Bird; The Man Who Came Back; and Quality Street. [122] p., 9 cm.
    - Notebook 23, 1902 (Box 24, Folder 745)
      Signed and dated October 1902. A partial list of contents: Fairy Play [Peter Pan]; Maartens Play; The Chemists Daughter [Little Mary]; Theatrical Essay a la Lamb; Play Parents return [Alice Sit-By-The-Fire]; Book of people coming back from the grave and resuming life [Dear Brutus]. [134] p., 9 cm.
    - Notebook 24, 1903 (Box 24, Folder 746)
      Signed and dated November 1903. [54] p., 8 cm.
    - Notebook 25, 1904 (Box 24, Folder 747)
      Signed and dated May 1904. A partial list of contents: Play for Miss Adams; 1000 Nightingales; The Second Chance [Dear Brutus]; The Successful Man; And The Old Warrior. [114] p., 8 cm.
    - Notebook 26, 1904 (Box 24, Folder 748)
      Signed and dated November 1904. A partial list of contents: Curly short stories (of a stage child); Peter Pan (revise); 1000 Nightingales; The Ladies Shakespeare; Good Ghost Stories; Theatrical People; Schoolboy; and one act play "A Bit of Colour." [114] p., 8 cm.
    - Notebook 27, 1905 (Box 24, Folder 749)
      Signed and dated July 27, 1905. A partial list of contents: The Beasts Hour Fairy Story; Peter; The Successful Man; Play, An Indictment of England; 1000 N's; Normandy; Play "The Cow"; Saints and Sinners Play; [An Afterthought]; [The Will]; [Old Friends]; [Rosalind]; Punch; Cinderella; Religious Play; and Too Old at 40. [118] p., 9 cm.
    - Notebook 28, 1905 (Box 25, Folder 750)
      Signed and dated 1905. A partial list of contents: Crichton (revise); Labour Member [play]; Cinderella play; Peter Pan Sketch Book; Taming of the Shrew; God-child play; The Ibsen Girls; and Charles Lamb theatre. [180] p., 9 cm.
    - Notebook 29, 1906 (Box 25, Folder 751)
      Signed and dated 1906. A partial list of contents: Revise Crichton character; 1000 N's; Voices; The Stolen Wood; Father and Son; Peter Pan; Schoolboy Papers; and Novel on The Accursed Thing. [78] p., 12 cm.
    - Notebook 30, 1907 (Box 25, Folder 752)